Johan, Axel REMILIEN

Madrid - Community of Madrid - Spain

☐ +34 677 244 031 • ☐ johanremilien@gmail.com • ☐ 34677244031

② johanremilien • in johanremilien • ☐ johanremilien ≥ 12080818/johanremilien

Software Development Engineer Qt | C++ | QML (since 2014)

Professional Summary

My journey in the software industry began in 2014, and since then I've continually honed my expertise, keeping up to date with the latest technologies and best practices.

My strong adaptability and commitment to delivering high-quality solutions make me an asset to your projects.

Education

ESIGELEC Rouen, Seine-Maritime - Normandy - France

General Engineering degree (major: Embedded Systems) 2011 - 2014

Work Experience

Senior Software Engineer Consultant & Founder

KOKLEEKO, Hybrid

July 2024 — Present Madrid - Community of Madrid - Spain, Hybrid

Skills: Software Development Life Cycle, Communication, Multitasking, Budget & Project management

Senior Software Development Engineer

IKKONIX SOFTWARE, Freelance

May 2024 — June 2024, 1+ month

Franconville - Val-d'Oise - Île-de-France - France, Remote

- [-] Migration from Qt Widgets to QML
- [-] Review and enhancement of the BL layer in connection with the UI

Skills: C++, Design Patterns, JavaScript, qmake, QML, Qt Widgets

Senior Software Development Engineer

EUROCONTROL, Freelance

January 2024 — April 2024, 4 months

Brussels - Brussels Region - Belgium, Remote

- [-] Enhanced multithreaded ASTERIX message-processing library by integrating modern C++ design principles
- [-] Measure and expand unit test coverage
- [-] Improve performance and mitigate the risk of memory leaks

Skills: Bash/sh, Bitbucket, C++, clang-format, clang-tidy, CMake, Unit test coverage, Cppcheck, Design Patterns, Doxygen, GCOV, GoogleTest, LCOV, LLVM, Linux, macOS, C++ STL

Senior Software Development Engineer

Dirac, Freelance

September 2022 — February 2023, 6 months

Uppsala - Uppsala County - Sweden, Remote

- [-] Development aimed at transitioning the tool from an expert-centric usage to a more consumer-oriented interface
- [-] Introduce the first unit tests (GoogleTest)
- [-] Migration from Qt 5.15 LTS to Qt 6.2 LTS on CMake, C++, and QML parts

Skills: Android, Bamboo, Bash/sh, Bitbucket, C++, CMake, clang-format, GoogleTest, iOS, JavaScript, macOS, QML, Qt5, Qt6, Windows

Senior Software Development Engineer

Televic Healthcare, Freelance

July 2022 — September 2022, 3 months

Izegem - Flemish Region - Belgium, Remote

[-] Simplifying the patient assistance interface for easier use by those with reduced capabilities *Skills:* C++, Embedded Systems, Qt Designer, Qt Widgets, Qt5, Unix

Senior Software Development Engineer

Pix4D, Full-time

December 2020 — March 2022, 1 year 4 months

Madrid - Community of Madrid - Spain, Hybrid

[-] Development of a drone-flight-planning mobile application Pix4Dscan *Skills:* Android, Bash/sh, C++, C, CMake, Concourse, Confluence, GoogleTest, git, iOS, Jira, JSON, Kotlin, Linux, macOS, QML, Qt Test, Qt5, Scrum, Swift, Unit testing, XML

Senior Software Development Engineer

Digital Essence, Freelance

June 2020 — July 2020, 2 months

Montreuil, Seine-Saint-Denis - Île-de-France - France, Hybrid

[-] Development and integration of a control panel in a projection mapping software HeavyM *Skills: Agile, C*+++, *QML, Qt5, Qt Widgets*

Software Development Engineer

Parrot Faurecia Automotive, Full-time

November 2018 — May 2020, 1 year 7 months

Paris - Île-de-France - France, Hybrid

[-] Development of audio tuning tools for music and speech quality enhancement of car sound systems *Skills: Agile, Bash/sh, C++, C, Confluence, Design Patterns Gerrit, git, HTML, Jira, Linux, QML, Qt5, TCP/IP, UI, UX, Windows, XML*

Software Development Engineer

PSA via Segula Technologies, Direct Contract

August 2018 — November 2018, 4 months

Vélizy-Villacoublay, Yvelines - Île-de-France - France, On-site

- [-] Development of a tablet application controlling a rolling autonomous-driving simulation, to study human reactions to vehicle interior configuration changes between autonomous and user driving phases
- [-] Development of a CAN-like communication protocol similar using TCP/IP sockets, allowing different HMI parts to be synchronised

Skills: Agile, Bash/sh, C++, CAN, Git, QML, Qt5, TCP/IP, Unix, Windows

Embedded Systems Engineer

Continental via Ausy, Direct Contract

May 2018 — August 2018, 4 months

Rambouillet, Yvelines - Île-de-France - France, On-site

[-] Specification, development, and validation of a tell-tales system connected to CAN bus *Skills: C, CAN, Enterprise Architect, Green Hills MULTI, Renesas RH850/F1L(176 pins), V-Model*

Systems Integrator

Visteon via Ausy, Direct Contract

September 2017 — April 2018, 8 months

Cergy, Val-d'Oise - Île-de-France - France, On-site

- [-] Hardware and software integration of level-3 autonomous driving equipment in a Volkswagen Golf GTI Mk7
- [-] Qt/QML expertise for Kanzi-replacement

Skills: Bash/sh, C++, CommonAPI, hrefhttps://franca.github.io/franca/Franca, Linux, NVIDIA Drive TM PX2, QML, Qt, vSomeIP

Software Development Engineer

Magneti Marelli via Ausy, Direct Contract

March 2016 — *June* 2017, 1 *year* 4 *months*

Châtellerault, Vienne - Nouvelle Aquitaine - France, On-site

- [-] Development of an objects library and a layout tool for a responsive infotainment system proof of concept
- [-] Development of equipment demonstrators for Faurecia presented at The Mondial de l'Auto (2 months)
- [-] Prototyping the evolution of the HMI of the Alfa Romeo Giulia on a bench in Modena, Italy (2 months) *Skills: Agile, Arduino, C++, git, JSON, qmake, QML, Qt5, Windows*

Software Development Engineer

PSA via Alten, Direct Contract

June 2014 — February 2016, 1 year 9 months

Vélizy-Villacoublay, Yvelines - Île-de-France - France, On-site

- [-] Development of a QML plugin for encapsulating CAN frames in TCP packets
- [-] Development of Citroën's concept car GUI, the AirCross
- [-] Taskforce for the delivery of the series life GUI of Peugeot, Citroën, and DS
- [-] Development of part of a DS concept car GUI, the E-Tense

Skills: Agile, Bash/sh, C++, CAN, Confluence, git, Jira, Linux, Photoshop, photoshop-qmlexporter, QML, Qt5, Windows, X11

Skills

Operating Systems Targets: Android, iOS, Linux, macOS, WebAssembly, webOS, Windows

Programming Languages: Bash/sh, C++, C, Java, JavaScript, Objective-C++, Python, QML, SQL, YAML

Build Systems Generators: CMake, qmake

IDE: Android Studio, Qt Creator, Qt Designer, Qt Linguist, Visual Studio Code, Xcode

DevOps tools: Bamboo, CocoaPods, Conan, Concourse, Fastlane, GitHub Actions, Google Test, RubyGems, Squish

Languages: English: C1, French: native, Martinican Creole: native, Spanish: B1